Your back is safe.
後面沒有危險
What is this place?
這是什麼地方？
It's not a subway,
不是地鐵
not a sewer...
也不是下水道
It kind of has the vibe of Torneko's dungeon.
感覺有點像 《特魯內克大冒險》遊戲裡的迷宮
Who's there?
誰在那裡？
Freeze!
不准動！
What was that?
剛剛是怎麼回事？
Sir!
警部！
It's Koki Shikazono, who went missing.
是失蹤的鹿園弘規
Mother.
母親大人
I am still unable
我到現在還是無法
to free my brethren trapped in the World of Nothing.
解放困在無間地獄裡的同胞
I'll think of something,
我會想辦法
A way for you to not have to kill anyone anymore.
讓妳不必再殺人
I promise you.
我一定會想出辦法的
It's all because of this human named Hachi.
這都是因為一個叫做小八的人類
Perhaps his kindness
或許是他的善良
has disturbed my heart.
擾動了我的心
Mother, please lend me your strength.
母親大人，可以借我妳的力量嗎？
Please give me a sign.
請給我一個徵兆
Welcome back. Hope you don't mind me here.
歡迎回來，我來打擾囉
Guess what I'm doing?
猜猜我在做什麼
I might be able to find the magatama you're looking for.
其實，我說不定能找出 妳在找的這塊龍勾玉呢
I'm trying the method I learned from Hikari.
我想運用跟小光學的方法
I'm breaking into my university's email server
侵入大學的電子郵件伺服器
and trying to find out about the magatama's owner through their IP.
透過IP位址尋找勾玉藏家的情報
I see.
這樣啊
What's wrong?
怎麼了嗎？
I feel stuck.
我感覺走進了死胡同
Enemy encounters keep increasing.
遭遇敵人的次數又不斷增加
But if you find the magatama, you can release your brethren, right?
不過，只要找到勾玉 就能解放妳的同胞了吧？
Why are you doing so much for me?
你為什麼要為我做這麼多？
I told you, we'll find a way not to kill.
我不是說過嗎？ 我們會一起找到不用殺人的方法
And I don't want to be killed by that zombie.
而且我也不想被那個喪屍殺掉
More than anything, I don't want to see your sad face.
最重要的是 我不想看到妳難過的樣子
Why do you have such a scary look on your face?
你怎麼表情這麼可怕？
It's Hachi.
是因為小八
He hasn't contacted me since we parted ways in that underpass.
自從我們在那條地下道分開後 他都還沒跟我聯絡
This has never happened before.
以前從來沒發生過這種事
I talked to him recently.
我最近有跟他說話
He wanted to know how to hack.
他想知道怎麼駭入伺服器
-You did? -Yeah.
–什麼？真的嗎？ –是啊
What the heck?
那個傢伙…
Damn him.
搞什麼啊
It's Benitaro.
是紅太郎
I have to go.
我得走了
I've got to open Hachi's eyes.
我得讓小八清醒過來
-Hey! Why did you ignore my call? -You ignored it!
–喂！你幹嘛不接我的電話？ –你不接電話！
I'm busy now!
我現在很忙！
Why did I get yelled at?
為什麼我要被罵？
PROFESSOR NATSUKO SAWADA
澤田夏子教授
Excuse me.
打擾了
There's something I wanted to ask you.
澤田教授，我有一件事想要請教
What's this?
這是怎麼回事？
What are you doing?
你在做什麼？
No, it wasn't me.
不…這不是我弄的
So, to summarize,
所以，情況是這樣
one, you found a mysterious post by Koki Shikazono.
首先，你發現了 鹿園弘規的這篇神秘貼文
Two, Koki Shikazono is still missing.
第二，鹿園弘規目前仍下落不明
Three, you accidentally summoned a Yokai named Izzy.
第三，你們不小心 召喚了名叫伊姬的妖怪
Why do I have to tidy up?
為什麼打掃的人是我？
Because you created this situation by summoning the Yokai.
因為都怪你召喚了妖怪 才會造成這個情況
No, Hachi summoned Izzy.
不，召喚伊姬的人是小八
Wait, so you believe what I said?
等等，所以妳相信我說的話？
So, is this also Izzy's doing?
那麼，這也是伊姬造成的嗎？
There's still Yokai energy remaining in this room.
這個房間裡還殘留著妖氣
How do you know that?
妳怎麼知道？
Professor Sawada is no longer coming to the university.
澤田教授不會再來大學了
Was she taken out by Izzy?
澤田教授該不會是被伊姬給…
I received an email from her this morning.
早上我收到她寄來的電郵
"I seem to have unintentionally entered a world I shouldn't have.
“我好像無意中 踏入了不該接觸的世界
"I will spend my remaining days quietly with Mitsuki.
“我會跟光希一起靜靜度過餘生
"Please don't look for me."
“請不要來找我”
I'm glad she's safe.
幸好她平安無事
It's not good!
一點也不好！
The Yokai shattered her mind.
妖怪摧毀了教授的意志
But at least she's alive.
至少她還活著就好
Hayato was...
哪像隼人…
What?
什麼？
Was Izzy the one who killed Hayato?
該不會是伊姬殺死了一本木隼人？
It's over! I have to go to the police!
不能再這樣下去，我得去報警！
You can't. This is a problem that goes beyond human understanding.
不行，這是凡人無法理解的問題
We need someone with special powers to deal with it.
需要特殊的力量來處置
What do you mean by special powers?
什麼意思？特殊的力量？
Aero.
浮空
Not good at all.
完全不行
-Yokai! -I'm not.
–妖怪！ –我不是
Then, what?
那這是怎麼回事？
You're so loud.
你太大聲了
If Yokai can use sorcery,
如果妖怪會使用妖術
it's not strange that there are humans with special powers.
那麼有人類具有特殊力量 能與之對抗，並不奇怪吧
I come from such a family.
我就來自這樣的家族
I'm still in training, though.
不過我還在修行中
Here. It's a cola float.
給妳，這是漂浮可樂
Because you seem down.
妳好像很沒精神，今天特別請妳喝
Even while I'm spacing out like this,
我在這裡發呆的同時
my brethren are suffering in the World of Nothing.
同胞正在無間地獄裡受苦
It's okay to have moments where you forget your mission.
偶爾暫時忘記使命，這也無妨吧
Fine.
好啦
I think I'll be able to find the owner of the magatama.
再給我一點時間 應該就能找到勾玉的藏家
I'm also analyzing it. This...
我有在分析，用這個…
No way!
不會吧！
-Misa! -Tadashi.
–美沙！ –忠士
Mom.
媽媽
Who is she?
這位是？
She's Izzy.
她是伊姬
Izzy.
伊姬
My girlfriend!
她是我的女友！
Wow.
哎呀
Madam, Ms. Misa. It's an honor to meet you.
母親大人，美沙大人 很榮幸認識二位
Hello.
妳好
He didn't tell us anything.
討厭啦，忠士他都沒告訴我們
Ms. Izzy, was it?
妳是伊姬小姐，是嗎？
I see. Nice to meet you.
這樣啊，真是的，初次見面
I'm Tadashi's mother. Thank you for looking after him.
我是忠士的母親，謝謝妳對他的關照
Are you serious? What's good about this dork?
不會吧？這種陰沉男有什麼好？
Dork?
陰沉男？
Actually, she also seems eccentric and crazy.
其實，她看起來也又怪又瘋的，超猛
-Hey. -What's this?
–別碰人家 –這是什麼？
-Okay.
–危險…
Careful!
危險啦！
Anyways, why are you here?
總之，妳們怎麼會在這裡？
We're preparing for today's party, of course.
當然是要為了今天的派對做準備啊
Don't tell me you forgot.
你該不會忘記了吧？
Of course not.
我當然沒忘
Hey, let's invite Ms. Izzy to the party, too!
對了，也邀請伊姬姊來參加派對吧！
-Hey! -Yes!
–喂！ –好主意！
"Party"?
“派對”？
Today is Dad's birthday, and we're going to celebrate.
今天是我爸的生日 大家要一起慶祝一下
I shall join you.
我願意參加
Please do.
請務必來玩
You know, a lot of his friends are gathering for a surprise party.
我們找了他很多朋友 一起籌畫一個驚喜派對
I sent an email to Tanuki as well.
我也有傳訊叫狸貓來
It's going to be lively.
一定會很熱鬧
That's not possible. Izzy has things to do. Right?
不行…伊姬還有事要忙，對吧？
Let's go.
我們走吧
See you later.
晚點見
You're going?
你們要走了嗎？
Don't forget to meet us at 6:00 at Minatoya.
派對晚上六點在湊屋舉行，別忘了喔
Her outfit is so unique.
不過，她的穿搭品味還真有個性
I feel like I've seen her somewhere, though.
我總覺得好像在哪裡見過她
There's no way Hachi can change Izzy.
小八以為能改變伊姬，但根本不可能
You can't change the personality of a killer.
殺人犯的本性根本不可能改變
I told Hachi that it's absolutely impossible. What do you think?
我告訴過小八 這是絕對不可能的，妳怎麼想？
Let's calm down a bit.
你先冷靜一下
So, we must find a way to send Izzy back to her world, right?
也就是說，我們得找出方法 把妖怪伊姬送回原本的世界，對吧？
Exactly. That's what I thought of asking Professor Sawada.
就是這樣 我原本正打算問澤田教授這件事
There might be some useful books in the library's archives.
圖書館的地下書庫 應該有些書派得上用場
What happened?
請問發生了什麼事？
Sir.
警部
We've expanded the search area, but no sign of the suspicious man.
我們擴大了搜尋範圍 但沒發現可疑男子的蹤跡
The suspect is armed. Find them at all costs.
對方有攜帶武器 不論如何都要把他找出來
Yes, sir. Let's go.
遵命，我們走吧
I still can't get a hold of Sakon Renjo.
我還是聯絡不上連城左近
We followed Sakon and discovered the underpass.
我們跟著左近，發現了這條地下道
We found the body of Koki Shikazono,
找到了鹿園弘規的屍體
and we were attacked by a suspicious man.
並遭到一名可疑男子攻擊
And now, we can't reach Sakon.
然後現在，我們聯絡不到左近了
We won't let him get away this time.
這次他不能再裝作什麼都不知道了
I'll keep calling until he picks up.
我會瘋狂打到他接電話為止
I'll send him texts, too.
對了，還要傳訊息給他
Where are you? Plz call. Plz pick up.
你在哪裡？請回電，連城先生？
Plz reply! Quick chat! 2 mins, or even 1.
為什麼不接電話？ 請回覆，講個幾句話
Plz reply or call back! 30 seconds?
一兩分鐘也行 請回電，30秒也好
The temple and the university are connected by such underpass...
那座寺廟和大學 居然能透過這樣的地下道連通…
What's that?
那是什麼？
I don't know.
不知道
But keep it.
好好保管
Sir, your phone has been ringing like crazy.
警部，你的手機從剛剛就一直在響
Yeah. I have something scheduled.
是啊，我跟人有約
What is it? Spit it out.
怎麼了？說清楚啊
It's actually my birthday today.
說來難為情，其實今天是我的生日
It's your birthday?
什麼？今天是你的生日？
Why didn't you say so earlier!
你怎麼不早說！
If you don't go, it'll be a family crisis!
如果你不去，會造成家庭破裂的危機
Can I take a short break?
我可以稍微離開一下嗎？
Leave things to me and enjoy your time.
這裡就交給我鈴木，請好好去慶生吧
Stop it.
別這樣
MINATOYA
你打給了一個 來自人類未知空間的妖怪
Leave a message.
留言吧
I'm sorry for not inviting you to the party.
伊姬，抱歉沒有邀妳來派對
My dad is a cop, so it'll be awkward.
我爸是警察，所以會很尷尬
I promise I'll make it up to you.
我保證一定會彌補妳…
-No need for that. -What?
–沒這個必要 –什麼？
Izzy!
伊姬！
I came to see your father.
我來見父親大人了
But I told you. My dad takes everything seriously,
我不是說了 我爸對待每件事都非常認真
and he'll be shocked if he saw your outfit.
他看到妳這身打扮會很震驚的
How about this?
那這樣呢？
-Is it strange? -Not at all.
–會很奇怪嗎？ –一點也不會
Let's go, then.
那麼，我們走吧
Wait! Just promise me one thing.
等等！答應我一件事
Keep the conversation light. No murder or severed heads.
聊輕鬆一點的話題 別提到殺人或砍頭的事
And don't give unnecessary details.
最重要的是，別回答不必要的話
If you don't understand, just say, "Wow, that's amazing!"
聽不懂的時候 只要說：“哇，太棒了！”就好
And if you're in trouble, signal me.
還有，要是遇到麻煩就打暗號給我
You might've seen before. It's the "help" sign I use with Tanuki.
妳應該有看過 這是我和狸貓之間的“求救”暗號
Try it.
妳試試
Let's keep a low profile, then.
那麼，千萬低調一點
-What? -Oh.
–什麼？ –咦？
Sorry, Mom. It's us.
抱歉，媽，只有我們兩個而已
Sorry, everyone. It was my son.
大家對不起，是我兒子啦
Please go back to your positions.
麻煩回到原位
What were you doing? He'll be here soon.
你在做什麼？你爸很快就要到了
Ms. Izzy. Nice dress.
伊姬小姐，這件洋裝真美
You look nice too, ma'am.
母親大人也很美
Thank you. It's been a while since I wore these things.
謝謝，我有一陣子沒穿這種衣服了
No one complimented me, so thank you.
都沒有人稱讚我，謝謝妳
Izzy, you're super cute!
伊姬姊，妳超可愛的！
Hachi's father's birthday party is here,
小八爸爸的生日派對要在這裡舉辦
so if Izzy is with Hachi, she should be here.
如果伊姬和小八在一起的話 她應該會在這裡
-Be cautious with Izzy. -Right.
–記得對伊姬保持警覺 –好
Act as naturally as possible.
盡可能表現自然一點
This is a mission to investigate Izzy's behavior.
這是一項調查伊姬行為樣態的任務
I'm in charge of Hachi and I'll leave Izzy to you.
我負責搞定小八，伊姬就交給妳了
I don't want to pee in this outfit.
我不想漏尿在這套衣服上
Sorry, everyone. Another false alarm.
對不起，大家，又搞錯了
Could you go back to your places?
麻煩大家再重新回到定位
-Thanks for coming, Tanuki. -Yes.
–狸貓你來啦，謝謝 –妳好
And this is?
這位是？
This is Arisa, she's a senior from my university.
這位是我大學的學姊，有紗
Sorry for coming uninvited.
抱歉突然跑來打擾
Not at all. The more the merrier.
一點也不，這種場合人越多越熱鬧
Please come in.
請進
Why are you two here?
你們兩個怎麼會來？
Well, you know.
就是，你知道的
We can't just let your dad's birthday go unnoticed, right?
你爸過生日 我們不可能不來祝賀，對吧？
You sound like you're hiding something.
這話聽起來好像在隱瞞什麼
Are you two...
你們兩個該不會…
-Well, yeah. -No.
–嗯，對啊 –不是的
No, we aren't.
不是的
No way! Awesome!
不會吧！太強了！
What skincare products do you use?
保養呢？妳都用什麼保養品？
Skincare. Hello?
怎麼保養皮膚？跟我說嘛
Excuse me.
我失陪一下
-Wow, amazing. -Your lips are so plump.
–天啊，好棒 –妳的嘴唇很豐滿
-What's this about? -Nothing.
–妳們在聊什麼？ –沒事
Are you all right?
妳還好吧？
You saved me.
你救了我
Misa is hard to understand.
美沙大人說的話很難懂
High school girls are all like that.
高中女生都是這樣
What's with that outfit?
妳這身打扮是怎麼回事？
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
Oh, no, nothing. You just look beautiful.
沒什麼，只是覺得妳看起來很漂亮
Hachi, come with me.
小八，過來，跟我來一下
Hey! Stop it.
等等！停！
You came to save me?
你是來救我的？什麼意思？
Izzy is a monster.
伊姬果然是個怪物
A body was found in that underpass.
那條地下道發現了一具屍體
That body is Koki Shikazono.
那具屍體就是鹿園弘規
So, he was already a zombie and Izzy just re-killed him.
怎麼說呢，他已經變成喪屍了 伊姬只是又殺了他一次而已
"Just re-killed him"? Do you know what you're saying?
“只是又殺了他一次而已”？ 你知道自己在說什麼嗎？
I can't take it anymore.
我受夠了
I'm so scared I might pee myself.
我超害怕，好擔心會漏尿
She saved me.
她救了我一命
Besides, killing a zombie is completely different from killing a person.
而且，殺死喪屍和殺死活人 完全是不同的兩件事
That wasn't murder.
那不算是殺人
What's with that philosophical anime excuse?
你怎麼會說出 這種哲學動漫風的藉口？
You're going insane.
你的想法很有問題
This is bona fide murder!
這就是貨真價實的殺人啊！
Hush!
你太大聲了！
Sorry, wrong person! Please go back!
對不起，你們搞錯了！請快點回去！
Don't do it again, Tadashi.
真是的，忠士，別再這樣了
-Come on. -Hurry!
–真是的 –快點回去！
-Quick! -Jeez.
–快一點！ –真是夠了
-Hurry! -What?
–快點！ –咦？
Everyone.
大家
No way.
不會吧
He's here.
他來了
Do you know how long it took me to prepare all this?
你知道這一切我準備了多久嗎？
I'm sorry I ruined the surprise.
對不起，我毀了這個驚喜
Cheers!
乾杯！
But I'm glad everyone is here to celebrate.
但是大家都來為他慶生，真是太好了
-Excuse me. -What?
–我失陪一下 –什麼？
Izzy, I found out who owns the magatama.
伊姬，我知道勾玉的藏家是誰了
Hikari helped me hack the mail server.
小光幫我駭進了郵件伺服器
I'll send you the owner's address.
我現在就把藏家的地址寄給妳 等我一下
Tadashi?
忠士？
It might be a good opportunity to introduce her to your father.
我想說你還是跟爸爸 正式介紹一下她吧
This is Izzy, Tadashi's girlfriend.
這位是忠士的女友，伊姬小姐
Girlfriend?
女友？
Today is a most auspicious occasion for celebration, sir.
父親大人，今日真是值得慶祝的吉日
She's quite traditional.
她是個古風女孩
Would you mind helping with cutting the cake, Izzy?
伊姬小姐，妳願意來幫忙切蛋糕嗎？
Cutting is my specialty.
切東西是我的專長
-You're 50... -Your girlfriend...
–50歲生日快… –你女友…
-Fifty is... -She's nervous...
–50歲是… –她很緊張…
Dad...
爸…
Happy birthday.
生日快樂
Thanks.
謝謝
So, that's your girlfriend.
那位就是你的女友嗎？
Show me my friend.
顯現出我的朋友吧
Hey.
喂
I'm busy. Come back later.
我很忙，你晚點再來
Your search should lead you to the police station.
你想找的人在警察局
Why'd you leave that corpse alone? And the underpass?
為什麼丟下那具屍體？ 還讓人發現了地下道？
Keep it down. The way to here has been sealed.
別慌張，通往這裡的路已經封起來了
Humans cannot see it.
人類是看不見的
The police are after me. Listen.
警察在追我，聽好了
Don't get involved with that corpse anymore.
別再跟那個活死人有牽扯
I don't want any more trouble. Got it?
我不想惹上更多麻煩，知道了嗎？
Now, everyone, it's time for the biggest show of the day.
各位，今天最盛大的表演時間到了
Lights!
打光！
Today's star, Tadayoshi Inukai,
今天的主角犬飼忠義
was a backpacker traveling in America,
去美國旅行當背包客的時候
when he had a fateful encounter in a café in Boston!
在波士頓的咖啡館邂逅了真命天女
There, he picked up Shizuka Inukai, who was studying at a university there.
他搭訕了在那裡留學的犬飼靜香
On their first date, they danced to this memorable song.
這首歌是他們第一次約會時 跟著跳舞的難忘歌曲
Everyone, please join in the dance tonight!
請大家也一起跟著跳舞吧
Music, start!
播放音樂！
It turned into something strange.
變成了奇怪的狀況
I'll make it stop right away.
我馬上叫她停下來
Since we're here...
既然都這樣了…
Happy birthday.
生日快樂
I wish your parents were here to see this.
真希望你的父母能見證這一切
Thanks.
謝謝
You know,
我啊
I left home at a young age
年紀輕輕就離了家
so I wasn't confident of having my own family,
所以一直沒有信心建立自己的家庭
but thanks to you, I've made it this far.
多虧有你，我才能走到這一步
I'm sorry for always leaving the house matters to you.
我總是把家裡的事都丟給妳，對不起
I don't say this often enough, but I appreciate it.
這句話我很少說出口，但我很感謝妳
Thanks.
謝謝
That means a lot.
我好開心
Izzy.
伊姬
I think it's okay to have moments where you can put your mission aside,
我果然還是覺得 偶爾暫時忘了使命也無妨吧
especially at a party.
派對就是這樣的場合
So maybe we can...
所以，或許我們也可以…
Forgetting one's mission is never allowed.
忘記自己的使命，是絕對不可原諒的
I see.
是嗎？
Of course. Sorry.
說得也是，對不起
Can I have a moment?
方便說句話嗎？
Girl talk.
女生之間的話題
Take it. It's work, right?
接吧，是工作的電話吧？
Sorry.
對不起
Hello?
喂？
I'm sorry to interrupt you, but I have something urgent to report.
抱歉打擾你慶生，但我有急事要報告
It turns out that Koki Shikazono, whose body was found,
原來，屍體被發現的鹿園弘規
was in a seminar led by Professor Sawada,
他的指導老師澤田教授
who recently took a sudden leave of absence.
最近突然休職了
-Leave of absence? -Yes.
–休職？ –是的
Her name is Natsuko Sawada.
是一位叫做澤田夏子的教授
There was a kind of diary,
她的研究室裡有一本類似日記的
or record of guidance, left at her lab,
學生指導紀錄
and according to that, right after Shikazono went missing,
根據上面的內容，鹿園失蹤後不久
she interviewed some student to inquire about Shikazono.
她曾在跟某個學生面談時 問到鹿園的事
Who is it?
那個學生是誰？
Well, it's your son, Tadashi.
他是…警部你的兒子，忠士
I wanted to be friends with you.
我想和妳交朋友
Please, use this.
不介意的話，請用這個
I'll accept this powder as a token of friendship.
我願意接下這個粉末作為友誼的象徵
Where did you learn to handle a knife like that?
妳是在哪裡學會那麼厲害的刀法？
My family is skilled in the use of various types of weapons.
我的家族擅長使用各種類型的武器
Are they hunters?
妳的家族都是獵人嗎？
If necessary, we hunt.
有必要的時候，我們也會打獵
Who are you?
妳是什麼人？
This is a problem.
真傷腦筋
Damn.
糟糕
In that case...
沒辦法了…
-Where's Tadashi? -I don't know.
–忠士在哪裡？ –天曉得
But his girlfriend is super cool.
不過他女友超帥氣的
I knew I'd seen her somewhere.
我就覺得好像見過她，終於想起來了
Her dance videos have gone super viral. She's famous.
她的舞蹈影片曾被瘋傳，很有名呢
I need to take a photo with her.
我一定要跟她合照
This is...
這是…
Answer me. Who are you?
回答我，妳是什麼人？
I know your true identity is a Yokai.
我知道妳的真面目是妖怪
Tell me everything you know.
告訴我妳所知道的一切
This is your first and last warning.
這是我第一次，也是最後一次警告妳
You're still alive because of Hachi.
妳還能活著都是因為小八
Don't you come any closer. Got it?
以後別再靠近我們，知道了嗎？
Do you really think he wishes to be with you?
妳真的覺得他想跟妳在一起嗎？
Your relationship is just a curse!
你們的關係終究只是個詛咒！
He fears being with you.
他害怕跟妳在一起
Deep down, he knows you're a monster!
他內心深處知道妳是怪物
Your relationship with him will never be more than that!
妳和他的關係永遠無法再進一步
I appreciate it.
謝謝
You reminded me of something important.
妳讓我想起了一些重要的事
Humans are foolish creatures who willingly hurt others.
人類是可以毫不在乎地 傷害他者的愚蠢生物
You humans are the true monsters.
你們人類才是真正的怪物
Until my brethren are free,
在同胞獲得自由前
I'll slaughter as many humans as necessary.
需要屠殺多少人類我都願意
Where the hell is this?
話說，這是哪裡？
Izzy. Where have you gone?
伊姬，妳跑去哪裡了？
Hachi.
小八
Arisa was left stranded on a distant bridge.
有紗被困在遙遠的一座橋上
Izzy threatened and abandoned her.
伊姬威脅她，還丟下了她
She wouldn't do that for no reason.
伊姬不會無緣無故這麼做
Are you still defending her in this situation?
在這種情況下，你還要維護她？
Hey, did you tell Arisa about Izzy?
我問你，你跟有紗說了伊姬的事嗎？
I told her. I had no other choice.
我說了，我別無選擇
Didn't we promise not to tell anyone about Izzy?
我們不是說好了嗎？ 別把伊姬的事告訴任何人
I was trying my best to keep everyone safe.
我一直在盡力保護大家的安全
It's your fault.
一切都是你不好
Why'd you fall for someone who kills people?
你愛上了一個殺人犯
Then, you stopped caring about the people around you.
然後就不再關心身邊的人了，對吧？
Am I right?
你說啊，是不是？
That's not true, Tanuki.
狸貓，完全沒這回事
Don't run away. I'm talking about something important.
不要逃避，我在跟你談重要的事
Tell me. If I get attacked by Izzy again,
告訴我，假如我又被伊姬攻擊
who would you pick?
你會站在哪邊？
No way.
不會吧？
What happened to you?
你到底是怎麼了？
Where's Izzy?
伊姬在哪裡？
She disappeared into the shadows.
有紗說她消失在影子裡了
Apparently, she's willing to kill as many people as it takes
顯然她為了解放自己的同胞
to free her brethren.
殺多少人都願意
I have to go.
我得走了
Hachi, she's a killer.
小八，她是個殺人犯
If you allow this, you're just as guilty.
也就是說，放任她的你也同樣有罪
I think you should follow your own path.
我想，你應該走自己的路
A path that has nothing to do with me.
一條跟我沒交集的路
I completely agree.
我完全同意
Where are you? Hey!
妳在哪裡？喂！
What's wrong? Call me!
怎麼了？快跟我聯絡！
Hachi.
小八
I realized who I am
我弄清楚了自己是誰
and what I must do.
以及自己必須做什麼
No more hesitation.
我不會再猶豫
The owner of the magatama is here.
勾玉的藏家就在這裡
NIJOJI
二淨寺
This is...
這裡是…
I didn't mean to surprise you.
我不是故意要嚇妳的
Reverend. I'm looking for a certain artifact.
住持，我在尋找某個道具
Could you help me?
你可以幫我嗎？
I believe we can help each other.
我相信我們可以互相幫助
Come, please follow me.
來吧，這邊請